Fake luxury goods like watches and shoes
make up 70% of the $2 trillion
counterfeit industry.
Here we have a
Burberry coat and it says Burbelly
mistakenly on the button.
Most people
think it's a victimless crime. What they
don't realize is they are the victims.
Counterfeit jewelry or handbags can have
dangerous toxins like cadmium and lead.
And knockoff sneakers have funded
terrorist attacks.
Oh, what's the harm
on just buying this pocketbook? What
could it do? The problem is where the
money is going.
Illicit factories are
making fakes that are so convincing.
Stopping them is getting harder. If
they
shut one down, another one is being
built across the pond.
So, how do
criminals smuggle counterfeit jewelry,
purses, and sneakers. And what can be
done to spot the real
stuff? Customs and border protection
officers are the first line of defense.
Steve Netherol is one of them. He works
at JFK airport's mail facility, which
receives about a million packages every
day.
When it's coming from China, being
that's your number one red flag.
In fact, most of the fake luxury goods
bound for the US come from China through
the mail system. In 2024, US customs
seized 32 million counterfeit items.
They would have been worth 5.4 billion
if they'd been genuine.
The most common counterfeited handbag is
Louis Vuitton. The most counterfeited
sneaker is Nike Air Jordans. The
manufacturer, they have to register that
product trademark protected with Customs
and Border Protection. And then if it's
deemed counterfeit, then we have the
ability to seize it.
Before a package
arrives in the US, CBP collects
intelligence on the sender, container,
and aircraft. That data along with
X-rays of the boxes help Steve's team
determine which ones are suspicious
enough to pull for manual inspection.
They're opening this package because it
came from a known counterfeitter in
Thailand.
We have Gucci eyewear, watches, jewelry.
The high-end manufacturers like this
never co-mingled their products. They
wouldn't put these items together, and
their items wouldn't come in bubble wrap
like this.
In 2024, knockoff jewelry was
the top commodity the US government
seized by value. It confiscated over
700,000 pieces, worth more than $1.6
billion.
This New Jersey jewelry store has just a
few people who sniff out fakes like
Michael Litman and his cousin
Gary. They're an authorized dealer for
brands like Cardier and David Yur. We're
buying straight from the company, so
there's zero risk there. The bigger
risk, of course, is is when we're buying
precious metals, gold or diamonds from
customers. If I make a mistake, it costs
us a lot of money.
Let's see what you got. Okay.
Gold is so
high now. It's such a great time to
sell.
What is it at now?
2909.
Wow.
Per ounce of pure gold.
I remember
when it was $40 an ounce back in the
day.
First, Michael runs what's called a
scratch test on the gold pieces on a
black stone made of quartz.
So, it's a
really nice chain. Looks pretty good.
I'm going to check the stamp to see if
it's
So, this is a a 14 karat stamp. So, I'm
pretty sure it's 14 karat cuz I can just
from feeling it. Basically, what I'm
looking for is anything to tell me that
it's not gold. It could be a
discoloration of the metal. It's
oxidation, stuff that uh doesn't really
happen to gold.
What's the difference
between 14 karat and 18 karat? What does
the carat mean?
It means what what
purity of gold? So if it's 14 karat,
it's approximately
58.5% gold and the rest is alloy
out of
24 karat, which very rare. I'm I'm
pretty sure this is going to come 14
karat because I'm getting a nice
a nice
scratch on it. If it was if it wasn't
real, it would be very light. I'm not
doing it in such a way that it it's
going to hurt the piece.
Then he dabs a
bit of nitric acid on it. If the gold
scratch remains, it's real. If it
disappears, it's fake.
The lines are
still there. So, I feel comfortable
these are supposed to carry.
But on
these earrings,
so I don't see any
stamp. It's feeling kind of hollow. I'm
a little skeptical because it's so
light when you tap it. It's it it sounds
it's almost like it's plastic
underneath. But let's scratch it and
see.
It's definitely disappearing a little
bit. You see right here?
Yeah.
When I
shave it down, I'm getting I'm getting
the outside coating of the plating off,
which reveals the true what's
underneath.
That is I'm pretty sure
plastic. Okay. So, I unfortunately I I
can't do anything with these.
Michael
would only buy these two chains and a
necklace from this load.
The rest, like these earrings, were
goldplated or metal and are worthless to
him.
So, this is 26.8 g. So, your price
for this is $1,247.
I really had no idea, but I figured 500
was a nice even number. So, I'm
delighted.
This gold will be melted and
refined, removing all other metals.
Assuming it's pure enough, we'll
actually make it into a new piece.
The cousins also have to be careful when
they're buying diamonds.
Today, I think
the biggest challenge is is the lab
grown showing up in jewelry, showing up
in people trying to sell that.
Chemically, lab grown are diamonds, but
attempting to pass them off as natural
earth mine diamonds is illegal according
to the Federal Trade Commission. But
fraudsters try to do it anyway because
mine ones are worth a lot more. The
prices for lab grown are maybe 20% of
what mine diamonds are. I'm talking new
resale. There's very little resale
value. Prices for lab grown have been
dropping tremendously in the last couple
years as there's much more supply.
How you doing? I'm Gary. Nice to see
you. Steve.
Steve. Pleasure. Sit down.
So, what do you have
today? Gary is
checking out two diamond rings and two
sets of earrings. I was cleaning out my
grandmother's jewelry box.
For years,
Gary relied mostly on this diamond
tester, which can easily spot fakes like
this one made of cubic zirconia, a
synthetic man-made material.
You see how
nothing is happening? There's no red
going. It's It's like it's like it's
touching nothing. It's not nowhere near
a diamond.
But the machine can't
differentiate lab grown from mind
because they're chemically identical. So
Gary invested in this new one called the
ID 100.
This is a $12,000 tester and
they're just going up in price. Doing a
whole spectral analysis on the diamond
is a whole another level of technology.
We can't live without it basically.
So
that would be like an X-ray machine and
an MRI.
Exactly. That's an excellent uh
analogy there. Yeah.
Some stones that
look like diamonds like this moisite can
also trick the old tester. Moisite and
diamond share the same heat conductivity
attributes and that's why it'll pass
this machine
but the ID 100 will catch
it
referred.
Okay, these most likely are
lab grown. So what we have here are
mined diamond from the earth not diamond
called a cubic zirconian not diamond
called moisite and lab grown diamond.
Gary's team only buys mine diamonds.
pass.
It's a diamond.
Oh, beautiful.
Woohoo. Okay, great.
I think the worldwide jewelry market's
$350 billion. So, there's tremendous
amount of goods coming from everywhere.
And the fakes keep getting better and
better and better.
Tiffany and Cardier are the two luxury
jewelry brands most targeted by
counterfeits. In 2021, CBP Cincinnati
sees $3.6 $6 million worth of fake
Cardier
bracelets. The luxury brand David Yur
has also had a problem with dupes.
We
used to see David German knockoffs a
lot. The fake pieces are very light. So,
this has weight to it. This has tension,
like the perfect amount of tension so
you can get it on and it's comfortable.
The the knockoffs will be flimsy. Uh the
quality of the stones will be darker.
The company has filed multiple lawsuits
against counterfeits, and it's won.
They've really clamped down.
Companies
go to such lengths to combat fakes
because their reputations can take a
hit. When a buyer doesn't realize
they've bought a knockoff bracelet and
it falls apart, they might blame the
real company, and over time, that could
erode consumer trust in the
brand. This is especially true when the
fake jewelry is made of subpar
materials. In fact, in 2019, an LA
jewelry store owner was arrested with 15
million worth of fake jewelry. Some were
2,000 times over the US limits of
cadmium and
lead. Footwear is another industry
riddled with
counterfeits, and that's a challenge for
secondhand sneaker stores like Image in
Queens, New York. Co-owners Shu Chang
and Greg Lamb have been authenticating
sneakers for 20 years.
Fakes gotten better back then. Fakes was
so much easier to tell. I'm talking
about the year like 2000. But now we
look at every detail. We even smell it.
The fake pair they use like a more toxic
glue. 80% of the time this shoe comes in
has been fake. Right off the bat, as you
can see, the color like the real pair is
like a like a darker red compared to the
fake one is like a lighter red. See how
it's more form? This one's like more
puffier, you
know. As you can see on the camera in
person, they look like two identical
shoe. For example, this is the fake one.
The toe box is a little bit darker than
the real pit. The real pair has a
lighter hue to it. The leather feel on
the fake pair is so much stiffer than
the real pair. The real pit is nice and
soft and plush. The shape as well. You
see the shape is more bulky looking. And
then while the real pit looks very sleek
looking,
Shu has to sniff out the fakes because
in this game his reputation is on the
line.
If I'm not sure, I'll put it aside
either. I'm not even going to try. If I
could take a $400 loss to make sure that
my customer gets a legit product, I will
do that.
Shu says right now, this Travis
Scott and Nike collab is the most
counterfeited sneaker on the market.
Anytime this pair comes in, we have
pairs available to double check them.
Make sure the threading is good, the sle
color and everything.
The image team
paid $800 for this pair, but they're
selling it for double because the shoes
are so popular and Nike released a
limited supply.
Fake companies going to
go, "Hey, huh, I can make a buck off
this. Why not?"
Nike is the world's most
popular shoe brand, so sneakers also
dominate the resale market. They make up
70% of the store's inventory. Iconic
pairs like these Jordan 1 OGs in good
condition can rack up a lot of value
over time. A size 9 and a half sold for
triple the price in less than a year on
the resale site StockX. Likely due to
the buzz from the last dance documentary
series,
we compared them to like are
there's only one Mona Lisa. Why is it
worth so much?
These were given to
friends and family of Sony um that
worked on the PlayStation. The they made
151 pairs of these only. Yeah. When we
bought in 2006, we paid like a,000
bucks, which was a lot.
It's taken Shu and Greg over two decades
to build their impressive collection.
This is Kobe's first signature Nike
shoe, a game worn and autograph by Kobe.
Here we have a Jordan 11 black and red
signed by the man himself, Michael
Jordan.
And everybody's favorite movie,
Back to the Future, Marty McFly, Nike
Mags. When this shoe came out, we first
opened, we didn't have no money to to
buy the shoe off auction. We opened a
credit card to go buy this shoe. You
know, we need a piece of history. We
bought the cheapest size 9 at auction at
like $3,000. This shoe in the market now
probably worth like 20 grand. I guess
you could say it was a good investment
opening that credit card. This
collection can really get you a nice
house, right? A condo.
[Music]
Greg and Shu buy most of their inventory
from other sneaker heads like Shaq
Lawson, a Business Insider employee with
over a hundred sneakers in his
collection.
How's everything, brother?
How's everything, bro?
Good. You been
good?
Been good.
So, what's up with you
today? What we got?
Brought some stuff.
Just want to see like what you guys
would give me for it.
Sure. No problem.
Let's see what we got the first. Oh,
wow. Look at these. We don't We don't
see these often anymore, man.
Nike foam
pod is supreme.
Shaq bought this pair
from Image 12 years ago for $500.
Right now, if you were to sell it on
your own, you probably get like 600 for
this pair.
It's held value for like over
10 years now.
Nike's enduring value is
why counterfeits go to such lengths to
trick sneaker heads.
They're all from
China. And the crazy part is people tell
me that the fake factory are a few miles
down from the real factory.
And these
fakes can be very popular among fans who
can't afford the real stuff. So much so
that sneaker heads are sharing
spreadsheets like this one, listing
hundreds of cheap fakes for sale on
Chinese e-commerce site CN Fans. $62 for
phony Jordan 11s, $55 Balenciaga dupes.
I don't like it cuz I only sell real
product in here. In my opinion, it's not
a good It's not a good look.
Shaq is
buying his sixth real pair on resale
this month.
I think I'm really set on
these. I think I'm going to try these
on. These are the black infrared sixes.
Pretty good condition. Michael Jordan
won his first NBA championship in this
shoe.
I like to put the laces
behind instead of like looping it in the
front. It's kind of a sneaker head
thing. Like we often don't tie our shoes
just cuz it's a easy slip on, slip off.
And it's just something about when you
get a new pair of Jordans and like you
just look at them and you're like feel
complete. I'm going to take them. So
26775. All right. I think I know the
exact spot to put them.
All right,
brother. Enjoy the rest of your day. All
right. Have a great rest of the new
year, too.
See you guys soon.
[Music]
We are now in my sneaker room, also
known as the kingdom.
Shaq has 140 pairs worth well over
$20,000, all tucked away in a back room
of his Brooklyn apartment.
You're never
going to hear me say, "I don't have
something to wear."
He bought the majority of them from
Image.
Every sneaker in here is tied to
a specific memory. This one to me is
special because I remember being online
for it with my little brother. These
specifically, I'll always remember. My
first time in LA, I wore these. These
are the Ben 23 Jordan 13s, and there's
only
1,734 pairs of
them. This is my favorite Jordan of all
time, the Air Jordan 13 Flynn. I've
had five pairs of these. I remember
wearing to school in elementary school
and someone stepped on it and I was
ready to fight. Not because they stepped
on my foot and it hurt, but just because
they stepped on these and I love them.
These are the very
first hype sneaker I bought. Just
holding this shoe, I'm getting
emotional. I think I actually just got
kicked out of college at that point. I
think I was like about 18 because I was
taking too many days off to actually
take my mom to appointments. My aunt
gave me $100 and told me, "Buy yourself
something that means something to you."
And uh the next day I got these. If I
lost everything in this room and still
had these, I'd be happy. These are my
Origin shoes. They're more than just
leather and stitching. It's like this is
a book of memories for me.
But even a veteran sneaker head like
Shaq has had his fair share of run-ins
with fakes.
The first time I tried to
get these shoes, I actually ended up
buying a fake. So, I spent about $500 on
this style shoe. And it was fake. And
the reason I found that it was fake was
because on these they say flywire, but
the font is in white. The pair that I
got,
it had it in pink.
He understands why people would buy
fakes on purpose.
I don't judge. Wear
what you can afford. Wear what you like.
I know that many sneaker heads are
against it. But then how do you call
someone who invests all this money into
fakes not a sneaker head in a way? I
never will take part of it cuz I don't
want to use real money to buy fake
things. You have a large community of
people who are enthusiasts who love
these shoes, who have to worry about
these fakes that are getting so good
getting circled in.
But it's not just collectors like Shaq
and Image that are contending with the
flood of
fakes. StockX, one of the largest online
sneaker resellers in the world, has
rejected over $80 million worth of fake
pairs since
2016. Counterfeiting detection begins
when a user makes an account. It starts
with everything from bot detection to
policy to uh seller identification. And
a lot of this is automated.
After a
verified user sells a pair of sneakers
through StockX, they send them to a
warehouse like this one, which sees
roughly 10,000 items a day. First, staff
scan the RFID chips, which manufacturers
often put in the box to track and
identify authentic pairs. Counterfeiters
even try to copy those. The company also
uses CT scans,
allowing us to get a
shape of what is under the hood. The
structure underneath the surface might
be slightly different if we're looking
at a counterfeit item.
Finally, a human
checks it.
I've been collecting sneakers
for way over 10 years. I verify from
Nike to Adidas to designer. So, pretty
much everything.
Anthony Tangarief can
inspect 250 pairs a day. First things
first, we're always going to start with
the box before we always get into the
shoe. Cuz believe it or not, boxes are
counterfeited as well. You want to look
at the fonts on the box label, the
border cuts, the
spacing fonts over here. Feel the
overall cardboard. Make sure it's not
too flimsy, not too
thick. Give it a little scratch test.
Comes with a mom and pop shop receipt.
Everything's checking out. Now getting
into the shoes. And basically what I'm
looking for is any types of factory
flaws, any loose threads, glue stains,
because our verification process goes
far beyond just real and fake. Something
wouldn't pass if it has a scratch on it.
And believe it or not, the smell. With
this particular shoe, you definitely
want to get a leathery smell. Nothing
too strong, nothing too chemically,
which counterfeits do tend to have. It
would smell anywhere between nail polish
remover, gasoline. Sometimes these would
pass our verification process.
Anthony
attaches a green StockX tag to the shoes
to tell buyers they've been
authenticated.
People have counterfeited our
verification tags and it went from a
basic green tag to a tag that now has QR
code that we use for internal purposes
to vet the product.
But some buyers say
this process isn't always foolproof.
StockX was found liable in March for
selling 37 pairs of fake Nikes on its
site. The company told us the products
in this case were a tiny fraction of the
tens of millions of shoes it's reviewed.
It's part of a lawsuit Nike brought
against the platform back in 2022. The
judge did however reject Nike's other
allegation that StockX willfully sold
counterfeits on its site. A decision
StockX touts as a win. But that hasn't
stopped customers and YouTubers online
from questioning the retailer.
Sometimes there are noise, there's
conversation that might exist on um on X
on Reddit. And we look at all of those
to make sure that these are outliers.
When there's 35 million people on the
platform every month, the the noise
isn't representative of the overall
view.
So, a lot of people are asking, is
it safe to continue to buy on StockX?
Will I continue to buy from StockX on
other platforms? Well, yes. This is the
Jordan 1 lost and found from StockX. and
knowing the rewards, knowing the risk.
That right there is pretty much the most
I'm willing to spend.
If StockX
authenticators do come across a fake,
it's either destroyed, turned over to
law enforcement, or returned to the
seller.
We do keep some items for
training purposes. I have the verified
past
one with an suspected and authentic.
Somebody would have been wearing this
outside. You're not going to call them
out. But now, if you get closer and
actually like take an in-depth look at
it, you're definitely going to sell.
Another industry that's fallen prey to
fraudsters,
watches. One of the most counterfeited
types of jewelry out there.
In my
perception, the demand for fakes is
simply because people like getting
something over on the man. Rob Holmes is
a private investigator for luxury watch
brands, just like his dad was in New
York in the 80s and 90s.
Canal Street was the epicenter for
counterfeit watches in the entire United
States. In Chinatown, they would be
standalone stores with big metal roll
down rollup doors. I grew up in the 80s
uh going on raids with my father and
making undercover buys. On raid days,
they would go with a van or a U-Haul
truck with uh offduty cops and firemen
inside the back back of the trucks and
they would have spotters along the way
who would go to local diners and tell
them the addresses where they've spotted
those watches that day. Then the people
would fly out of the trucks and um if
they didn't if they didn't get there in
time and the guys rolled down and locked
the doors, we had industrial uh
industrial strength saws where we could
saw through those locks. It wouldn't be
uncommon for my father to come home with
a U-Haul truck full of bags, hefty bags
full of counterfeit watches.
Today, you
can still find watch dupes lining Canal
Street.
As a person who has been dealing with
these things for years, when it doesn't
say Swiss, you know something's wrong.
John Buckley, a veteran watch reseller,
has spent 28 years trying to spot the
knockoffs.
You didn't pay $75,000 for this watch.
This is not authentic.
100% no bueno. First of all, this rotor
is not gold. Finishing is a mess. All
the best. Unbelievable.
John comes to New York City's Diamond
District to look for real ones for his
clients. He buys and sells about a dozen
watches a week.
Little Eddie's got a paddic that I need.
Hopefully, I can buy it from him and I'm
going to show him a couple of pieces
that I've got.
What's good about this watch? It comes
fully complete. Look at the condition.
You got everything.
He's hoping to get
this rare protect Philippe for under
$40,000.
Listen, I know it's it's a nice watch.
I'm not I'm not here to beat you up. You
know, I need it. 36,000.
I thought I was pretty good at 35.
$37,000. That's my final price. I think
it's fair. You can think about it. I
don't have to think. Maz.
No problem.
You're the man. Thank you.
This watch
will be sold for 40 40,000 and change.
So, I'll make three grand on the watch,
which is not bad.
John says he rarely makes more than a
few thousand per watch. Sometimes it's
only a few hundred.
There are very few
home runs in this game. I mean, I don't
know what is considered a home run.
Making 10 grand on a watch. It's like
that doesn't happen.
Down the street, John has his eyes on a
gold Rolex Day Date with diamonds on the
bezel.
How much is this $21,000 watch?
25,000.
Factory diamond dial. Factory diamond
bezel.
235. The deal. But I'm going to do for
you. I'm going to obviously say yes, but
really it's beautiful.
Thank you, Yasha.
John typically buys watches he knows one
of his clients is looking for.
We like
cash flow. I write a check. I want to
know that, you know, I'm going to have
that money back. I'll make my profit on
it and move on to the next one.
He
doesn't want to risk getting stuck with
something he might not sell, even if he
loves it. like this diamond studded
Rolex from Cutter, which has an asking
price of $175,000.
I I don't have a home for it.
Thank you.
These watches are so pricey
because they're partly assembled by hand
with premium materials like gold and
platinum, and there aren't many new ones
entering the market.
Brands like PC Philippe and Odmar Pujo
make fewer than 100,000 watches per year
and its estimated Rolex makes a million
annually which is not enough to keep up
with demand. Today a Rolex Daytona model
is so popular it's almost impossible to
get one.
I'm still on a waiting list
since 1996 just to give you an idea.
For
most people the only way to get one is
to get one secondhand. The result of
that in many cases is higher demand than
available supply which causes prices to
go up.
Between 2011 and 2021, Rolexes
outperformed the Dow, real estate, and
gold. In 2017, this Rolex owned by actor
Paul Newman sold for a record 15.5
million.
It is history now. 15,500,000.
And the US government's proposed tariffs
could drive the price of used Rolexes up
even
more. But as demand soarses, watch
dealers have to be even wier of
counterfeits. The biggest trap of the
trade.
You used to see watches that
would just have maybe one of the
trademarks, like just the crown on the
face, but not the crown on the dial. Now
manufacturing has gotten so good that
even the cheaper knockoffs have
everything.
Back at his workshop, John
is testing whether this Rolex from a
dealer in the southern US is
counterfeit.
Movement's working
properly. Movement is right. I mean, I'm
looking at the color of the case. This
piece is not the same color as this
piece. This is 18 karat gold. We always
have to check cuz I can't take a chance
on paying for it. number one or selling
it to someone else if I'm not sure.
So, he runs these gold Rolex parts
through that same scratch test we saw
earlier in the jewelry shop. He adds a
few drops of nitric acid, dissolving any
material that isn't gold.
The acid did not dissolve the gold. Over
here, the acid dissolved the gold. It is
not authentic.
But most of the time, he
can spot a fake with a naked eye. We
could usually spot these just based on
on the symmetry of the case, they don't
have that nice
Rolex slope. The other I mean obvious
thing that you look at. If you look at
the amount of space between the face and
the glass, you will see that it is very
high. It's probably got an extra
millimeter and a half.
But sometimes the only way to tell is by
opening up the watch. There's no
mistaking a Rolex movement from a
counterfeit. I don't care how good the
Chinese factories are.
And dealers like
John can't get it wrong.
New young bucks
that come into the business, they get
caught out there real fast and your
reputation is burned. Burned. When you
can't make good on a sale, you can never
spend enough money to get your
reputation back, you know? So, whatever
it costs you to keep it, it's worth
every penny.
[Music]
Luxury bag resellers like this pawn shop
in Queens, New York, also go to lengths
to protect their reputation against
fakes.
When a customer brings in a bag
to sell, authenticators like Vanessa
Cabrera use an app called Entropy to
verify it.
This one is also in very good
condition. As you can see,
if this
Chanel cross body is real, it could be
worth over
$5,000. She uses this iPod with a
microscope attachment to take detailed
pictures. The Entropy app will use these
to create what the company calls a
fingerprint for the bag.
We take a
picture of the handbag in between the
blue square and then they ask us for a
hardware logo photo. So now they ask
them for the serial
number. Entropy uses AI to compare these
photos to millions of images of real and
fake bags already in its database.
That was quick.
It's that extra layer of
confidence. Without the right tools in
your back pocket, you can never be 100%
sure. Easy Pawn's president, Lauren
Kaminsky Goldman, was the one who took
the chance on entropy. Today, she
brought in this vintage 2002 Chanel ring
hobo bag for Vanessa to authenticate. If
it's legit, it could be worth over
$1,000.
But what's your gut telling you?
The
leather looks good. The stitching as
well, it looks very clean. This one
doesn't have a day go. So that makes me
think that it probably is not. I'm going
to take a picture.
I don't want to.
[Music]
So we have the result for the
authentication of the Chanel and it's
authentic.
Yay.
Entropy says its software is right 99%
of the time, but if it does get it
wrong, the company will pay out duped
customers. We met with its CEO,
Vidyosin, in his office in Manhattan,
New York.
This is a fake that we
recently came across. High quality,
great workmanship, craftsmanship. You
see the leather, you see the the heat
stamps. This is actually one of the
items that we got incorrect. Entropy
refunded $2,000 to the customer who
bought this. When his team comes across
fakes, Vid Youth asks them to wear
gloves.
If you look at any report, any
data report, you will see that almost
all the counterfeit samples tested will
have some kind of harmful chemical or
toxin or metal, heavy metal in them. And
most of them are in areas that consumers
use. Maybe the handle, maybe the
buttons, maybe the zipper. It is an
upside down world that has amazing
world-class distribution. They've been
tied to things like terrorism.
In the 2000s, al-Qaeda suggested selling
fakes as a way to fund criminal
operations. And the brothers who mounted
the 2015 attack on the Charlie Hebdo
newspaper may have funded their weapons
by selling fake Nikes. While trafficking
counterfeits can lead to serious
consequences like millions in fines and
years of jail time, it generally carries
less risk for criminals than trafficking
drugs like cocaine or heroin. For
Vanessa, sometimes these counterfeits
are easy to spot by
eye. On fake ones, you don't see this
finish. They use different type of
lining inside.
But the hardest bags for her to
authenticate Hermes
They're common targets for counterfeits
because they're so pricey. So those can
take entropy days to verify. So this is
one of the most sought after handbag
names on the resale market. This is an
Hermes Kelly. It actually was a family
heirloom. So these things get passed
down in families.
The most prized possession in the Hermes
world is a Birkin. Some models can cost
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
They're not just giving it to any person
who walks right through the door. There
is a whole process of building a
relationship with the store, buying
other items maybe to kind of build up
that trust enough in you as a client.
Maybe then a sales rep will invite you
to buy a Birkin. They're so hard to come
by.
That's why they're so popular on the
secondhand market. From 1980 to 2015,
the resale value of Birkens outperformed
gold and the S&P
500. Jamie Chua, a Singaporean
influencer, has one of the largest
collection of Hermes bags in the world
with over
200. This is a oneofa-kind Birkin bag
that was made for me. It has this uh
Indian embroidery called the Oruran
embroidery. These are useless.
You can't put anything in them. Maybe
like like a credit card and a piece of
tissue. In the event of a fire, which is
not going to happen, of course, I would
grab my diamond
bag because I can go straight to
Christies. I know they're eyeing it.
This Himalayan crocodile birkin with
white gold detailing and 245 diamonds is
one of the most expensive Birkens in the
world.
They're made completely by hand out of
pricey materials like alligator calf and
ostrich skin.
It takes days to make this
bag. The craftsmanship, the materials
that go into it.
That's why they're a
common target for
counterfeits. One ring operating out of
France had actual Hermes employees
smuggling real materials and hardware
into its factories.
Fake Birkkins, which don't have the same
level of craftsmanship as the real ones,
have even been sold right alongside your
groceries. Walmart is making headlines
for selling a bag that's a knockoff of
an iconic luxury item. Third party
sellers put up the listings of the dupes
on the Walmart site for about $100, and
it went viral with customers calling it
the Walmart Birkin or the Workin. My
working from is here. We're going to
unbox it together. Okay.
That is so pretty. Actually, if you were
to go back to 2007 and someone was
wearing a Louis Vuitton bag, they
probably wouldn't be so quick to say,
"This is fake." Whereas today, I think
it's a little bit more um commonplace
and acceptable to be like, "Girl, I this
is not real. I paid $300 for this."
Dupes are also on the rise because the
cost of authentic luxury bags has
ballooned in recent years. Chanel has
increased the price of its most popular
bag by 75% since 2019. In 2023, Hermes
raised the price of its basic Birkin by
10%. Some people say, you know, there's
no way a bag can cost $20,000 no matter
how great the leather is. I think they
kind of might see that as a way to
protest and push back that like you can
make this bag cheaper because it exists
in a cheaper form already. But even if
the working can pose as a proverbial
middle finger to expensive brands,
there's still some ambiguity surrounding
it both ethically and legally.
You're
not 100% sure who made it and what their
working conditions were like. So, I
think that aspect is a little bit, you
know, is what should give people pause.
While the very cheap price might make it
clear the workin wasn't real, some
language in the listings may test the
legal boundaries, like having Birkin in
the title. According to the intellectual
property lawyer Ryan Clarberg,
but even
in the instances where the third party
sellers on the website do not use the
trademarks Birkin and Hermes, these
sellers may be breaking the law because
the distinctive shape of the Birkin bag
is itself protected by IP rights.
Walmart stopped selling Birkkins in
January
2025. Now, if you search Birkin on
walmart.com, all that comes up are what
look to be real Birkens listed for as
much as $50,000.
If I could afford $40,000 for a Birkin,
I probably would want a $40,000
purchasing experience. I'm going to need
a glass of champagne or
[Music]
something. But even more counterfeited
than handbags, clothes, remember StockX
apparel made up half of all suspected
fakes it found in 2024.
I would say the hardest part probably
the extensive catalog cuz we constantly
update our catalog so we get a lot of
products. Taper Pratt has been verifying
clothes for StockX for 3 years.
Anything
that has like a high price point or
that's like highly soughta are very
fake.
Like hoodies made from the brand
Fear of God. Today, Tay is verifying a
Stuy Nike collab sweater worth over $100
if it's real.
The first thing I
personally do, I'm going to look at the
quality of the neck tag. Nike neck tags
have embroidery for their logo. So, I'm
making sure that embroidery looks nice
and clean. I'm making sure again the
size tag looks nice and clean. And since
it's a a collab with Stusy, I'm looking
at the opposite side as well, and I'm
looking at the embroidery on the Stousy
logo. I'm next going to go to the actual
hang tag itself. All Nike hang tags have
a specific color for each size. So, I'm
going to look at the rib. I'm making
sure that's shiny and reflective. But,
we're also looking if the item is
actually used or not and in perfect dead
stock condition. There's no dirt marks,
no lint, no peeling.
This one was real,
so it'll be listed on the site. Tay has
come across fake versions of this
sweater. Pay attention to the coloring
with the fake one. It's way lighter than
the real one. You can see the color
differences between these reds. Like
this one's almost a pink color and this
one's like a stark bold red. You can
feel the quality, too. Do you see how
like loose this fabric is? And this one
kind of holds its integrity. This one's
pretty close. They got this pretty
close, but if you actually look at the
tag itself, you can tell it's lower
quality.
These fakes can be made with everything
from toxic dyes and flammable materials
to dangerous metals.
Even when you wash
it multiple times, these chemicals still
stay there. It can literally be anywhere
on any product that you purchase that is
counterfeit from any source, online or
offline.
Luxury heels can fetch similarly high
prices, especially ones with an iconic
red bottom. Christian Louis
Vuitton. Terresa Romer, an author and TV
personality based in Houston, Texas, has
over 560 pairs of shoes, 100 of which
are Louis Vuitton.
This is actually my
favorite favorite pair of Christian
Louis Vuitton. Who wouldn't want to wear
these? It's like wearing jewelry on your
feet, right?
These are so expensive because each pair
is made by hand. That's why these heels
can start at
$600. Even used pairs that have been
refurbished can fetch a lot. That's why
Vincent Ralph, a cobbler in New York
City, charges up to $95 to resell these
worn out pumps.
When you have a painted
soul such as this one, the paint's going
to wear right off as soon as you take a
few steps.
Vincent sands the shoe and
adds a red sole protector. Take your
hammer. I'll start applying the sole
nice and
evenly all around the shoe.
Then I'll
cut the sole, glue it on, and sand it
down some more. He then mixes three
paints, a red, scarlet red, and flat
white to try and match the iconic Louis
Vuitton color. Back to its former glory,
this pair might fetch hundreds of
dollars. That price is part of why
authorities have come across a lot of
fakes. The Fed saying they have seized
more than 20,000 pairs of counterfeit
high heels by designer Christian
Louisboutuitton. In 2012, customs
officers in Los Angeles found the shoes
in five shipments. What tipped them off
is the boxes were coming from China, but
real Louis Vuitton are made in Italy.
The shoes would have been worth $18
million if they'd been real. Meaning
that each pair, had it been genuine,
would have been sold at $1,200 a pair.
So that's a big loss for our revenue had
they have entered the commerce of the
United States.
But how do criminals make and move so
many luxury counterfeits globally? Well,
most operate in China or Hong Kong.
Wherever manufacturing is cheap, that's
where manufacturing is going to happen.
These factories can afford the same
machines that the real companies use.
And they use the same software. Often
that software is stolen through
industrial espionage.
They also might
smuggle products out of the real
factories so they know what to
replicate. But they'll swap the
materials for cheaper, lower quality
ones to reduce costs. But sometimes
those materials are toxic things like
lead, cadmium, and arsenic, which can
cause rashes and even cancer.
I don't
think health and safety of consumers is
a top priority in their business model.
These factories also pay low wages and
can have unsafe working conditions.
There have been plenty of stories of the
counterfeit watch industry being tied to
child labor, sweat shops, and even human
trafficking. You're going to have
organized criminals who are doing this
kind of stuff.
They might make a fake
listing through online marketplaces like
Amazon or enlist the help of
influencers. Social influencers in some
instances will direct their followers to
what we call generic links where they
will say buy from this store or this
seller in the Amazon store when they're
having back channel communications
through DMs and such with their
followers about the counterfeit nature
of a luxury bag.
Counterfeits even use
AI to create fake social media posts
that might look something like this.
To get these dupes and fakes into the
US, factories will simply ship them
through the international mail system in
small, low value
packages, like the one Steve Nethersol
team finds at JFK International Airport
in New York City. Oo, we have Nike
sneakers here. Take the box, crush it
up. This is obviously to save space.
This is not traditional of the
manufacturer if this was authentic to
crush all these items in here like this.
They don't put any of this in it, the
filler inside it.
Brands will send Steve
an information kit on the real products
and telltale signs of fakes. Most of
what's in these kits is kept top secret
to protect the brand against
counterfeits. But Steve could share a
few things.
Rolex would never put their
watches in little Ziploc bags. They
don't put these inside it, the silica
gel. Rolex does not send to individuals
in the United States. They only send to
their retail stores. Here we have a
Burberry coat and it says Burbelli
mistakenly on the button.
But for CBP to
seize anything, there has to be a
trademark on that product.
See what we got in here. Shirts. Yes,
it's all Suzuki shirts. Suzuki has
motorcycle and car trademark, but not on
apparel. So, this will end up being
released.
Next, Steve figures out what
this item would have cost had it been
real. what's called the MSRP.
This one here would be about $11,000.
That's the MSRP. What the manufacturer
would be losing had this been genuine.
From 2020 to 2024, the number of annual
CBP seizures more than doubled and the
total MSRP value of those jumped as
well.
Here we have a postcon full of
seizures. So, it's going to go into the
storage room.
In the end, all these
products will be destroyed.
So, what happens to the
counterfeits? For one, Homeland Security
Investigations or HSI can decide to open
up a case, but Steve says that doesn't
happen often to the HSI agent. There's
only so many of them. They're going to
deal with the most important thing,
which is narcotics. All the fentinel and
the cocaine that come that are killing
people. That is a top priority, and it
should be. The second problem, American
authorities don't have jurisdiction in
China, where a lot of counterfeits are
made. In 2023, HSI arrested 434 people
on suspicion of counterfeiting. Just
over 200 were
convicted. Today, you'll still see fake
products ponded off on the streets of
New York. In fact, in 2022, the NYPD
sees $2 million worth of fake bags from
Canal Street.
But most seizures start online.
Platforms like Amazon, Alibaba, and eBay
have spent hundreds of millions of
dollars fighting these fakes. Amazon,
the world's largest online retailer,
launched a counterfeit crimes unit in
2020. Through Project Zero, brands can
send Amazon info on their trademarks and
even take down fake listings themselves.
Amazon also uses AI to scan an estimated
8 billion listings every day. in the
instance that a bad actor attempts to
load a logo that is counterfeit or that
is fake that our models can pick up on
those labels and take that down
proactively.
In 2023, Amazon said it
took down about 700,000 fraudulent
accounts and last year it seized and
disposed of 15 million counterfeit
products
worldwide. The platform might also take
these counterfeits to court.
We've partnered um for example with uh
Valentino on a civil suit against a bad
actor who was infringing on Valentino's
brand.
Or Amazon might send the
fraudsters data like IP addresses,
physical addresses, and bank account
info to law enforcement
so that they can
take quick action against these bad
actors and conduct enforcement raids and
seizures. Amazon partnered with US
Homeland Security to seize 10,000
counterfeit car grills.
Counterfeits are agnostic to the types
of products that they're selling. They
may have automotive parts, but they're
also going to have uh luxury goods as
well.
Amazon has also partnered with
Chinese law enforcement to raid
factories making fake luxury goods.
Europole also conducts raids. In 2021,
it seized $18 million worth of luxury
items from a criminal ring in Spain.
In 2024, it busted an Israeli ring
selling counterfeit watches in Antworp.
That same year, a joint Europole
operation led to the seizure of 99
million worth of fake clothes, shoes,
and accessories and nearly 400 arrests
across 17 countries in Europe.
It grows every day, and it's because of
consumer demand. People need to be
educated more about the dangers. So, if
you're in the market for a luxury
handbag or a secondhand pair of kicks,
how can you protect yourself?
I tell
people whether you're going to buy a
product or you're going to have a
product repaired, go to an authorized
dealer.
Do not buy counterfeit products.
Try as much as possible to get certified
products.
If you can put more thought
into the ethics, then I definitely think
buyers should
And always be wary of a
really good deal.
And the old saying, if
it seems too good to be true, it
probably is.
Let's go look at it.
[Music]
Look at it.